好
okay
我要搬过去，房租就给你缴了
I'm moving out,so you're in charge of paying the rent.
对哦，什么时候要缴？
-When's it due?
1号 每个月吗？
-On the first. -And that's every month?
不是，你想住的月份才要缴
No,just the months you want to live here.
这是电话费
Okay,here's the phone bill.
上帝啊
Oh,my God!
那是我们的电话号码
That's our phone number.
是我突然决定要搬走的 所以我先帮你挡一阵子吧
I know I kind of sprung this me-moving-out-on-you thing.Why don't I cover you for a while?
不行 乔伊崔比亚尼不接受施舍…
No way!Joey Tribbiani does not take charity...
再也不了
anymore.
这不是施舍… 不行，别再说了
-It's not charity,Joe. -Forget it.
谢谢，但我不想再拿你的钱了
Thanks,but I'm done taking money from you.
我可以照顾自己，还有什么？
I can take care of myself. What's next? Come on.
好，这是电费
Here's the electric bill.
用个电要这么多钱？ 对
-This is how much we pay for electric? -Well,yeah.
其他的账单以后才看咯？
So we'll do the rest of the bills later,then?
本集播出：“最后一夜”
The One On The Last Night
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
那乔伊得搬出去吗？
Will Joey have to give up the apartment?
希望不用 我想给他钱，但是他不收
I offered him money,but he wouldn't take it.
你觉得他需要多少？
How much does he need?
我想1千5应该够他活几个月
$1500 would cover him for a few months...
但我得骗他收下 免得伤害他的自尊
but I have to trick him into taking it so I don't hurt his pride.
你怎么不雇他当演员？
Why don't you hire him as an actor?
你可以在你需要的任何时间叫他扮演短剧
You could have him dress up and put on skits whenever you want.
那样对自尊确实有帮助
Well,that would help the pride thing.
你真是美呆了 明天要不要搬来跟我住？
Wow,you look great! Do you wanna move in with me tomorrow?
好啊 好
okay！ okay！
你们女生今晚要做什么？
Any plans for tonight?
与其难过我和瑞秋要分开 我们觉得不如去吃饭庆祝…
Instead of being sad on my last night with Rachel...we're going out to celebrate
瑞秋要搬去跟菲比住
Rachel's moving in with Phoebe.
还有我的生日 今天不是你的生日
-And also my birthday. -It's not your birthday.
真不给面子 我从来都不会戳穿你
What a mean thing to say! I'd never tell you it wasn't your birthday.
你们男生有什么节目吗？
You guys have anything planned for the big last night?
与其待在一起胡混 我们决定这次什么也不做
Instead of just hanging out,we figure we'd do nothing.
今晚是尼克队首战
Knicks' season opener tonight.
我以为你们会想来我家看
I thought you'd come and watch it.
算了吧，罗斯
I don't know,Ross.
我怕你又吹说你放弃打球 去当古生物学家
Not if you talk about how you gave up basketball to become a paleontologist.
我本来就放弃打球 去当古生物学家
I did give up a career in basketball to become a paleontologist!
菲比，我在想… 你还没换衣服？
-Phoebe.. -You're not dressed yet?
我们15分钟后就要去玩了
We're supposed to start having fun in 15 minutes!
很显然，时间还早
And clearly,not a minute sooner.
你都打包好了吧？拜托你说是
You are packed,though,right? Please tell me you're packed?
我当然打包好了，你别紧张
Of course I'm packed. Monica,relax.
我只是想问菲比我该穿什么
I wanted to ask Phoebe what I should wear.
天哪，我真是一刻也不得闲
My God,I can't get a minute of peace.
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
莫妮卡会宰了你
Monica's just gonna kill you.
我知道 你穿这样蛮适合被杀的
I know.What you're wearing is fine for that.
瑞秋，我…
Rachel，I…
你没打包！你根本一点都没动
You're not packed!You're not packed even a little bit!
惊喜
Surprise!
什么？ 你别发飙，是这样的
Don't get mad,because this is what happened.
我开始打包
I started packing,
然后想到：我在干嘛？ 我最不会打包了，对吧？
then I realized,"What am I doing?"I am lousy at packing,right?
但你最爱打包了 所以做为我的临别赠礼…
But you love packing!So as a gift to you on our last night....
我可以当总指挥
I'll be coordinator!
对不起，我没帮你准备礼物
Oh,my God,I'm so sorry. I didn't get you anything.
大家都要帮忙 菲比你可以帮忙吧？
Everybody has to help. Phoebe,can you help?
我有约会
I have plans.
你是跟我们有约会 没错
-You have plans with us. -That's right.
钱德可以帖纸箱，罗斯封箱 乔伊搬东西
Chandler can make boxes,Ross can wrap and Joey can lift.
菲比，去通知男生帮忙 好
Tell the guys they have to help out.
天哪，谢谢你
My God,thank you!
快逃，莫妮卡要叫你们收东西 她把工作都分好了
Monica's gonna make you pack! She's got jobs for everyone!
我是躲不掉了，你们快逃
Now,it's too late for me,but save yourselves!
搬家公司11个小时后会来 瑞秋还没打包
The movers will be here in 11 hours. Rachel hasn't packed.
每个人都得帮忙
Now,everybody has to help.
钱德，你先从… 不行，我和乔伊有事
Chandler..I have plans with Joey.
你不是说你们没事？ 这是最后一次了嘛
-You said you were doing nothing. -Yes,but for the last time.
好吧，罗斯…
Fine. Now,Ross..
我没办法帮忙 为什么？
-I can't do it. -Why not?
不是班要来吗 因为班要来
-Don't you have Ben? -Because I have Ben!
都快8点了，他都快上床了 他在哪里？
It's almost past his bedtime. Where is he?
他去参加晚宴
He's at a dinner party.
他真的要来？我看得见你家喔
He's really coming? I can see in your apartment.
当然是真的了
Of course he is. What?
难道我会拿儿子当借口？ 你把我当成哪种爸爸？
You think I'd use my son as an excuse?What kind of father do you think I am?
好吧，对不起
All right. Sorry.
我得做个班的人偶
I gotta go make a fake Ben.
来了，室友时代最后的披萨
Here it is.Our last pizzas together as roommates.
我不知道你会买披萨 我叫了中国菜
I wish I knew that. I ordered Chinese.
没关系
Well,that's okay.
其实这样蛮好的 我们最后的两人晚餐
In a way it's kind of nice. You know?Our last dinner together.
我带我祖先的食物 你带你祖先的食物
Me,bringing the food of my ancestors，you,the food of yours!
乔伊，我有个比较奇怪的想法
I had an idea for what to do on our last night.
我们来打几盘赌钱如何？
What do you say we play a little foosball for money?
你疯啦？自97年伤后复出 你就没赢过我
Are you crazy? You haven't beaten me since my injury-plagued '97 season.
你拿钱送我还比较快 是啊
-It'd be easier to give me your money. -Yes,it would.
你觉得50元如何？
What do you say to $50?
我会对它说 50元，你比我的财产还多
I say to it: "50 dollars,you are more than I have."
既然知道会赢，为什么不赌？
If you know that you'll win,what difference does it make?
好，赌了 好，开赛
-You're on. -Okay,let's play.
大战，意大利对… 当然是中国队
The big game. Italy versus...China,apparently.
看，是直排轮鞋 天哪
Look,it's the Rollerblades.Oh,God!
记得我们什么时候买的吗？
You remember when we got these?
不记得
No
那你当时应该不住这里
I guess you weren't there.
喂，我们说过要开心的
You guys,we said we were gonna have fun.
别这样，记不记得那次…
Come on. Hey,remember the time....
你们不记得吗？
You don't remember?
对不起，要搬走我真的很难过
Sorry,Phoebe. I'm just really sad that I'm leaving.
我会很想你
I'm gonna miss you so much.
其实不必这么难过
This doesn't have to be so sad,though,you know?
别再想你们会想念对方了 想想你们不愿意想起的事
Instead of thinking about how you'll miss each other...you should think of the things you're not gonna miss.
我觉得没有 总会有一两件
I don't think there's anything.Come on,there's gotta be something.
没有，她太完美了
She's perfect.
我有一件
I have one.
很好，你先说
Okay,you can go first.
我不会忘记 你不准我把留言笔拿走
I guess I'm not gonna miss the fact...that you're never allowed to move the phone pen.
说得好，莫妮卡，你有吗？ 瑞秋会把留言笔拿走吗？
That's a good one. Okay,Monica,anything?You know,does Rachel move the phone pen?
有时候会
Sometimes.
其实每次都会
Always,actually.
这就对了，这样不是好多了？
There you go. Doesn't everyone feel better?
不只是留言笔
Not just the phone pen.
我老是收不到留言 你收到啦
I never get my messages.You get your messages.
你在沙发上睡着 而我只有去看你的手背才知道留言应该不算
It doesn't count if you have to read them off your hand...after you've fallen asleep on the couch.
那你是没接到谁的留言？ 钱德还是你妈？
So you missed a message from who? Chandler?Or your mom?
还是钱德？还是你妈？
Or Chandler?Or your mom?
太好了，成功了，没人难过了
It worked! No one's sad!
万岁！我又赢了 你已经欠我5百了
I win again!That's,like,500 bucks you owe me!
5百元能买很多电对吧
Man! Five hundred dollars.That is a lot of electricity,huh?
我得买点吃的
I gotta buy some food.
给我捞本的机会 骤死赛，一球…1千
Give me a chance to win my money back. Sudden death...one goal,$1000.
真的？ 当然
-You serious? -Yes!
好，准备欠我钱吧 好
Get ready to owe me.
来吧，好了吗？
Here we go. Ready?
别~~想赢我
No...one can beat me!
看吧，所以只有小假人 可以出脚
That's why only the little fake men are supposed to do the kicking.
罗斯…看吧，还有别人会给我打电话
Hi,Ross. See,other people call me!
哦，是你哥哥，你赢了
Oh,your brother. Score!
怎样？
What's up?
我跟班在一起，想跟你问个好
I'm here with Ben.Thought we'd say hi.
让他听电话
-Put him on.
班，跟莫妮卡姑姑打招呼
-Ben,say hi to Aunt Monica.
看来他现在不想说话 不过他在笑
I guess he doesn't feel like talking right now.He's smiling,though.
好，待会再聊
Okay,talk to you later.
爸爸本来会成为篮球运动员的
You know,Daddy was gonna be a basketball player.
我觉得你们难过时比较好
I think it was better when you guys were sad.
记得这双直排轮鞋吗？
Hey,remember the Rollerblades?
你知道我还不会怀念什么？
You know what else I won't miss?
我是莫妮卡 我一天刷十七次马桶
"I'm Monica.I wash the toilets 17 times a day,
就算有人坐在上面也照刷
even if people are on it!"
我是瑞秋 我的毛衣太紧了吗？
"Hi,I'm Rachel. Is my sweater too tight?
不会？那我得洗一洗让它缩水
I'd better wash it and shrink it!"
我是莫妮卡 都没有有趣的人留言给我
"I'm Monica. I never get messages from interesting people."
我会打给她
I call her.
天哪！我爱罗斯，我恨罗斯 我爱罗斯，我恨罗斯
"Oh,my God! I love Ross. I hate Ross. I love Ross. I hate Ross!"
天哪！我交不到男朋友
"My God! I can't find a boyfriend.
干脆到对面去看到谁就上谁
I'll stumble across the hall and sleep with the first guy I find there!"
拜托，这可是最后一夜了
You guys,come on,this is the last night!
你说得对 所以我再说最后一次
Yeah,you're right,and so for the last time I would like to ask you:
滚出我的房间
Boo-hoo. Get out of my room!
如果想赶去餐厅就得快了
We should get a move on if we want to make those dinner reservations.
还是坏的？
Still broken?
真是烂透了
It sucks,man.
你在这里的最后一晚 我却失去两样最重要的东西
Your last night,and I lose the two most important things:
足球台和5百元
The foosball table...and $500.
有别的办法可以把钱赢回去 要不要玩二十一点？
There are other ways to win back your money. How about blackjack?
我不擅长玩二十一点
Not my game.
那就玩… 我们可以玩个新游戏，很好玩
You know what? We can play a new game.It's fun!
叫什么名字？
What's it called?
杯牌
Cups.
我不会玩杯牌 我教你，来嘛，简单又好玩
-I don't know how. -I'll teach you. It's easy and fun.
好吧 好，拿牌
-All right. -Here you go.
我有两张皇后，你呢？
I have two queens. What do you have?
二和五 你赢了，50元
-A 2 and a 5. -You win! Fifty dollars!
真的？ 没错，再玩
-Really? -Let's play again.
你是什么牌？
-What have you got?
四和九 你在开玩笑吧？
-4 and a 9.You're kidding,right?
怎么了？ 那是满杯
-No. Why? -That's a full cup!
我真是杯牌高手
Damn,I am good at Cups!
我不要跟她说话
I'm not talking to her.
总得有人先开口
You have to take the first step...
这个人应该是你 因为她要搬走，她比较难过
because she's the one who's leaving. It's harder for her.
也许你是对的…但她嘲笑我的留言笔
Maybe you're right.But she made fun of my phone pen!
我知道，我也觉得很过分
I know. I took it hard too.
她正在里面哭，我听得见
She's in there right now,crying. I can hear her.
她没有在哭
She's not crying.
她正在忍，真勇敢，快去吧
She's holding it in. She's so brave. Go.
瑞秋，刚才的事我很… 你在干什么？
I feel bad about what happened..What are you doing?
把东西拿出来 什么？
-I'm unpacking. -What？
我不搬了，这幅画正吗？
I'm not moving. Is that picture straight?
离左边差了20条街
It needs to go about 20 blocks to the left.
你知道吗？ 是你要改变，跟钱德同居
You're the one who wants this big change and to move in with Chandler!
你才应该走，为什么要我走？
You should go! Why do I have to leave?
因为这是我的房子 它也是我的，还有呢？
-It's my apartment! -It's mine too! What else you got?
还有就是你要搬出去
How about: You're moving!
这样太可笑了
This is ridiculous.
我们应该帮你打包
We should be packing you!
你们谈得怎样？ 很好，莫妮卡要搬走
-Hey,how you guys doing? -Great. Monica's moving.
我才没有
I am not!
是吗？那为什么你的东西 都在这个箱子里？
Really? How come all your stuff is in this box?
好，我知道是怎么回事了
Okay,you guys,I think I know what's going on here!
喂…停
You guys? Stop!
你们是假装生气，以免舍不得
I know you're acting mad because it'll make it easier to leave.
其实内心深处你们还是很难过
But deep down,you're really sad. Deep,deep down.
不，我很生气
-No,Phoebe,I am mad!
最最最深处 我就是很生气
-Well,deep deep deep down! -I'm just mad.
那就继续追吧
Then keep running.
你赢了
You win!
你是什么牌？ 不重要，什么都比不上三和六
-What did you have? -Nothing beats...a three and a six.
那叫D罩杯
That,my friend,is "D Cup."
你目前为止赢了多少？
How much have you won so far?
哇，7百
-700.
不是正好7百吧？ 是啊
-Not 700 exactly?
再加一倍 什么？
Double it.
在杯牌里，一旦赢到7百 就得自动加倍
In Cups,once you get $700,you have to double it.
真的？ 规则又不是我订的
I didn't make up the rules.
拿到加码奖金后 你可以拿一张牌
Now,after you receive the doubling bonus,you get one card.
那张牌有可能值1百元 让你总共赢得1千5
That one card could be worth $100,which brings your total to $1500.
别太兴奋，除非你拿到… 不会吧
Don't get excited,that won't happen unless you get the.. No way!
这是最后一箱衣服
This is the last box of your clothes.
我会在上面注明 “你在想什么？”
I'm just gonna label it "What were you thinking?"
有意思，我正想到对面 在钱德身上那样写
I was just gonna go across the hall and write that on Chandler.
两位，不是我想让事情变得更糟
Guys,I don't wanna make things worse,but...
但我不想跟瑞秋住了
I don't wanna live with Rachel anymore.
什么？ 你们对彼此太残忍了
You're so mean to each other.
我不想跟瑞秋翻脸 我还是喜欢你
I don't wanna end up like that with Rachel. I still like you.
没关系，因为我不搬了
That's fine because I'm not moving.
菲比，你一定要收留她
Phoebe,you gotta take her.
我说了很多她的坏话 但瑞秋也有一些好室友的特质
I said some bad stuff...but Rachel has qualities that make her a good roommate.
是吗？举个例子莫妮卡？
Like what,Monica?
她有147,000双靴子
She has 147,000 pair of boots.
真是个好例子，莫妮卡
Good start,Mon.
她会借给你穿
She lets you borrow them.
然后你再用你的大脚把它撑大
And you stretch them out with your big old clown feet.
你想睡路边吗？天气要变冷了
Do you wanna live outside? Because it's getting cold!
她有一大堆目录
She gets tons of catalogs
她会把我会喜欢的部分折起来
and folds down the pages of things I'd like.
还有呢？
What else?
我洗澡时 她会在镜子上留言给我
When I take a shower...she leaves me notes on the mirror.
我做的，是我做的
I do. I do do that.
真好 我喜欢浴室里有东西可读
That's nice. I like having things to read in the bathroom.
我在沙发上看书看到睡着 她会帮我盖毯子
When I fall asleep on the couch...she covers me with a blanket.
我不希望你着凉
Well,you know,I don't want you to be cold.
当我说我要跟钱德同居时 她非常支持我
And when I told her I was gonna move in with Chandler...she was really supportive.
你真好，你让事情变得很容易解决
You were so great.You made it so easy.
现在你要走了 我得跟一个男生住了
And now you have to leave.And I have to live with a boy!
不会有事的
It's gonna be fine.
瑞秋，我真希望你赶快搬进来
Now I can't wait to live with you!
而且我们应该把莫妮卡也带来 一定会很好玩
You know what we should do?Bring Monica,and we'll live together! We'll have so much fun!
但是她要跟钱德住 也对
I think she's moving in with Chandler.Oh,that's right.
你还是要跟他住吗？
You're still set on that?
应该吧
Kind of.
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
莫妮卡，打包顺利吗？
How's the packing going?
班？他很好，他就在…妈呀
Ben? He's fine. He's right.. Oh,my God!
把头从衣服里伸出来儿子
Get your head out of your shirt there,son!
什么？ 对，是南瓜，我过去帮忙
Yeah,it's a pumpkin. I'll come pack.
怎么了？
-What's wrong?
罗斯和我帮忙打包，在休息时
-Ross and I were helping pack...took a little break.
我跟他玩杯牌输了1千5
I lost $1500 to him in Cups!
玩杯牌怎么会输？ 跟你输的方式一样
How did you lose at Cups?The same way you lost!
我先拿到王和皇后 砰！罗斯拿到2和3
I started out with the king and the queen. Bam! Ross gets a 2 and a 3.
然后我拿到杰克和王 砰！罗斯拿到4和5
Then I get a jack and a king. Boom! Ross gets a 4 and 5.
罗斯拿到满杯，D罩杯 和自动加码
Even Ross was getting the Cup card,the D Cup...the sitting-down bonus.
我连半副杯牌都凑不到
I didn't even get half a cup! Nothing!
天哪
Oh,man!
他之前也没玩过 我觉得玩杯牌都靠新手的牌运
He never played before either.I think beginner's luck is very important in Cups!
好，我们再玩一把
Let's play one more hand. One more hand.
不要，我1毛钱也输不起了 我是说真的
No more! I cannot lose another dime. I'm serious this time.
事实上，我要送你一样东西
In fact,look.I wanna give you something.
现在就送 免得我为了杯牌的赌债拿去当
Let me give it to you before I pawn it for Cups money.
我要把大白狗送给你 谢谢你这些年来的照顾
I want you to have the big,white dog as a thank-you for being such a great roommate.
我不能收，你很喜欢这个雕像
I can't take the big white dog. You love it.
他不是雕像，他是活的
It's "him." Not "it."
要是我跟你买呢？
What if I bought it from you?
你可以以合理的价格卖给我 1千5如何？
Then your nice gesture would be giving it to me at a reasonable price.Say $1500?
等一下，我知道你想干嘛了
Wait a second. I see what you're trying to do here.
你又想塞钱给我
You're trying to give me money again!
我什么时候塞钱给你了？ 之前看帐单的时候
When did I try to give you money?Over there with the bills!
你想施舍我 我说不要，你也就算了
You tried to give me charity,I said no,you dropped it.
然后我们开心度过最后一晚
We had a nice last night together.
说笑，赌钱，谁也没塞钱给谁
We had some fun,we gambled,nobody tried to give anybody any money.
现在你突然又想来这套
Now you start with the charity thing again!
我只是想帮助你 我想确定你的生活没问题
I'm trying to help you out. I wanna make sure that you're okay.
我会没问题的，你听着
I will be okay.
你不能老觉得我无法照顾自己
You gotta get it out of your head that I can't take care of myself.
我不会怀念你借钱给我
I'm not gonna miss you helping me out with money.
我唯一会怀念的  就是你
The only thing I'm gonna miss...is you.
现在还有这只狗
And now the dog.
到了打电话给我，好吗？ 好
-Call me when you get there,okay? -Okay.
我真的会很想你
I'm really gonna miss you.
钥匙要还你
I have your key.
拿去 谢谢
-Here you go. -Thanks.
天哪，多好笑 再过几小时就会见面了
God,this is silly. I'll see you in a couple of hours.
房子再见
Bye,house.
再见
Bye
她真的走了 我知道
-She really left. -I know.
谢谢你 不客气，室友
-Thank you. -No problem,roomie.
我可以问你一个问题吗？ 当然可以
-Can I ask you a question? -Sure.
那只狗怎么会在这里？
What the hell is that dog doing here?
我捏造了杯牌规则好塞钱给乔伊
I invented the game of Cups as a way to give Joey money.
现在你想把钱要回去？ 没错
-And now you want that money back? -Exactly.
钱德，你以为我是白痴吗？
What kind of idiot do you take me for?
没有那种牌，那是我捏造的
It's not a real game. I made it up.
很遗憾你的钱没了 但我赢得光明正大
I'm sorry you lost your money. But I won it fair and square.
游戏是假的
At a fake game!
如果你想赢一点回去 我愿意陪你玩
If you wanna try to make some of it back...I'd be glad to play you for it.
但我必须警告你 我是杯牌高手
But I should warn you.I am very good at Cups.
好，你上次玩 有出现杯盘牌吧？
I assume the saucer card came up when you played last.
没有
No
看看这次会不会出现
Let's see if it comes up this time.